firmo holanda

CEO at viize computing

firmo@viize.com

Summary

IT professional with over 10 years of hands-on experience in VMware virtualization, Zimbra Email Collaboration Server, Linux System Administration, network infrastructure, and Microsoft technologies. Focused on providing top-notch support and technical ability to help businesses reach the next level, using the latest technology coupled with long term stability.

Experience

IT Consultant

March 2008 - Present

- Number of migration projects based on VMware 3.5, 4.x and 5.x. Provisioning hosts and servers according to client specification, deploying and managing VMs (ESXi, vSphere, vCenter, etc). Creating clusters and pool resources, setting reservations and limits, defining alarm triggers. Assigning HA, FT, DRS technologies according to client expected uptime and recovery needs.
- Real time infrastructure monitoring providing support to the cloud infrastructure, maintaining high availability and optimizing performance through proactive measures.
- Provide remote and field based system support (tier 3) on running infrastructure. Reporting to project manager, sending updates and progress reports.

it manager

March 2004 - March 2008 (4 years 1 month)

- Installation: desktops, peripherals (printers, scanners), cabling, basic network devices (routers/modems, switches), backup, antivirus, monitoring tools and 3rd party software. Patching all windows based systems.
- Configuration: networking (TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP, VLAN, NAT), internet connection (DSL, ADSL, ACL), services and roles (ADDS, print server, file server), user accounts, setting permissions, creating Group Policies, redirect network shares, WSUS, IIS 7 deployment.

trainee

2001 - 2003 (3 years)

Level 1 IT support.

Education

Unifor

computer engineering, 2001 - 2005

University of Delaware

computer engineering, 1999 - 2001

Activities and Societies: National Solar Decathlon, Design and Livability student Leader.

McKean High School

1998 - 1999

Activities and Societies: Honor Roll, Blue Hen Conference, Varsity Athletic Award, Delaware Secondary Mathematics League, Outstanding Citizenship Award, National Honor Society.

Colégio Christus Anexo

1986 - 1998

Activities and Societies: T. A. of computer classes

firmo holanda

CEO at viize computing

firmo@viize.com



Contact firmo on LinkedIn